creditsesame.com 2011-12-27

# Privacy Policy | Save Money with Credit Sesame

**Date Last Revised: October 1, 2010**

We recognize that your privacy is of utmost importance and take it seriously. This Privacy Policy describes Credit Sesame's policies and procedures on collection, use and disclosure of your information when you use Credit Sesame's site. This policy does not apply to information we collect through other means such as offline. For more details on site usage, please refer to Credit Sesame's [Terms of Use](http://www.creditsesame.com/how-we-help/terms-of-use/).

### Information Collection and Use

Credit Sesame uses the information we collect to do things like: analyze your credit and debt factors, find you personalized loan offers, maintain security, personalize content, remember information such as your email address, more efficiently access your account and set monitoring alerts. We also monitor aggregate metrics such as total visits and time on site.

**Information You Provide:** The information that you provide - including name, date of birth, email, real estate ownership, home address, social security, and any information about your finances (income, assets, debt, credit) - is used only to automatically and securely collection your personal financial information from trusted partners and is never sold to third parties.

Some of your information - such as name, address, social security number, and financial information (credit and debt) - is retained in encrypted form so that our system can continuously look for pre-qualified loan and mortgage offers through our proprietary algorithm.

We may also obtain personal information about you from our business partners and other third parties (for example, if you provide Credit Sesame your social security number so that we can retrieve monthly updates on your credit score and debt information from the credit Bureaus, or if you provide your address so that we can retrieve and track your current home value). In these cases, we will request your explicit permission.

We may use your name and email information to send you service related notifications, including any notices required by law. You can control the receipt of service related messages on the "Accounts" page. We may also send you marketing messages. You can always opt out of marketing messages by following the unsubscribe directions within the email message.

In the mortgage, loan, refinance or debt restructure application process, we may request and collect from you personal information of others, such as information about a co-borrower. The requested information may include social security, name, address and other financial as well as personal information for the co-borrower.

**Friend Invite:** If you choose to use our invitation service to invite a friend to Credit Sesame, we will ask you for your friend's personal email address to send an automatic invitation message. Credit Sesame will store this information to track the success of our invitation functionality.

**Blog and Community:** You may also provide us information in the community and blog sections of our site. This information is publically available and may be searched by search engines.

**Contests, Sweepstakes and Surveys:** In case of Credit Sesame related contests, sweepstakes or giveaways, any information you submit will be protected by this privacy and security policy, unless otherwise noted by the contest or sweepstake rules. Occasionally, we ask our users to take surveys to help us improve the site usability and product offering. Information provided for the survey will be used for survey purposes only and protected in accordance with Credit Sesame's Privacy Policy.

**Testimonials:** We may request customer testimonial for public use. The testimonials may require personally identifiable information such as your name and state of residency. When requesting testimonial or customer identifiable information, we will always require your consent.

### Use of Cookies and Other Automatic Information Collection of Capabilities

**Cookies:** When you visit and register on our site, we may send cookies (small data files) to your computer and browser to uniquely identify your browser and better understand usage and activities of our site. Cookies may convey anonymous information about how you browse and navigate through our site, but they do not store personal information about you. Additionally, we may use cookies to personalize website content for your needs, help you login faster and enhance your navigation through the site. While most browsers accept cookies automatically, you can always delete or modify cookies by following instructions on your browser. If you choose to delete or modify our cookies, you may not be able to access some parts of our site.

**Clear GIFs Information:** When you use our website, we may employ clear GIFs (also known as web beacons) which are used to track online usage patterns of our visitors anonymously. They do not store personal information about you.

**Disclosure:** This site uses ClickTale web analytics service. ClickTale may record mouse clicks, mouse movements, scrolling activity and any text you type in this website in order to increase web usability. ClickTale does not collect personally identifiable information that you do not voluntarily enter and does not track your browsing habits across web sites which do not use ClickTale services. For more information see the [Privacy Policy for Information Collected by the ClickTale Web Analytics Service](http://www.clicktale.net/disable.html). You can disable this service at any time at <http://www.clicktale.net/disable.html>.

**Information from Other Sources:** We may collect personal and non-personal information from our trusted partners and other sources. With your explicit permission, we may collect your credit score and other components of your credit report, such as existing loan amounts, monthly payments and the like. This is to determine your credit worthiness. We may also collect your current estimated home value or other personal or financial information to verify the accuracy of the information you provide.

### How We Share Information You Provide

We may share information you provide, as described above, with some of our business partner and trusted service providers to provide a service you requested, to comply with legal requirements, or to provide you with additional offers from our trusted partners that may interest you. However, we will never share your credit information with anyone without your explicit written permission.

In case of mergers, business dissolution, purchase or sale of business assets, we may share customer, email and visitor information needed to complete such transactions.

**Authorized Service Providers:** We may share personal information with our service partners and lenders when you choose to apply for a loan, mortgage, refinance, debt restructure or one of our financial offers. These providers require financial and personal information to complete your loan application and verify your eligibility for the requested product. When you submit the Loan Application, in the event that you are approved for the loan, we may share your information with third party investors to whom we intend to transfer your loan after closing.

**Legal Disclosure:** In case of judicial request, court order, or any other legal process, we reserve the right to share your personal information as required by law, to protect our rights.

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information:** We may share non-personally identifiable information - such as website usage, visitors, number of clicks, bailout rates from certain landing pages and referring URLs - with interested third parties to help them understand the usage statistics of our site. In these cases, we will not provide personally identifiable information.

### How We Safeguard Your Information

To protect your personal and financial information, we use numerous procedural, electronic safeguards that comply with federal regulations: 

  * We use firewalls, secure data transfer and encryption mechanisms to protect your information from any misuse, unauthorized changes, access or loss of data.
  * We conduct regular testing and scanning to ensure customer safety.
  * All personal and financial information is encrypted before transfer through 128-bit SSL with 2048 bit key. This is the strongest encryption method available for the internet and is used industry-wide by leading banks and financial websites. Encryption ensures that the information passed through our site is confidential.
  * We use password encoding before it is stored in our database. User passwords are protected from Credit Sesame employees and stored securely.
  * To provide additional protection, we use a "time out" feature that automatically logs out inactive users and requires reentry of login user name and password credentials before returning to the secure site.

### Changes to Privacy Policy

We may update our current privacy policy with new information or changes. If so, we will update the Privacy Policy landing page as well as the "last updated" date to indicate the latest changes. All changes will take effect immediately after posting.

How to Contact Us: If you have any questions or comments regarding our privacy policy, please email us at privacy@creditsesame.com or write Credit Sesame, Attn: Privacy and Security, 440 N Wolfe Rd, Sunnyvale CA 94085.
